<metadata><idinfo><citation><citeinfo><origin>Metropolitan Council - Metro Transit</origin><pubinfo><publish>Metropolitan Council - Metro Transit</publish></pubinfo><pubdate>20180508</pubdate><title>Transit Stops - Itinerary Stops Only - Change Log</title><onlink>https://gisdata.mn.gov/dataset/us-mn-state-trans-transit-stops-itnry-chng</onlink></citeinfo></citation><descript><abstract>The Transit Stops Change Log layer contains active transit stops that are part of a transit route itinerary in the Twin Cities seven county metropolitan area. The layer flags when a stop is removed or added from pattern itineraries.

 The dataset includes attributes from the primary transit stop database maintained for MetroTransit and for customer information for other transit provider transit services. The locations are mapped referencing road centerlines following the GAC standard along with streets generated internally at Metro Transit. </abstract><purpose>To identify stop locations in the Twin Cities metropolitan area where transit services actively use.</purpose><supplinf>Twin Cities 7 county metropolitan area.  This includes the counties of Anoka, Carver, Dakota, Hennepin, Ramsey, Scott and Washington.</supplinf></descript><timeperd><current>Transit Stop information is updated weekly; pre-2023 has been seperated into it's own Feature Class.</current><timeinfo><sngdate><caldate>Updated Weekly</caldate></sngdate></timeinfo></timeperd><status><progress>Complete</progress><update>Weekly</update></status><spdom><bounding><westbc>-94.012</westbc><eastbc>-92.732</eastbc><northbc>45.415</northbc><southbc>44.471</southbc></bounding></spdom><keywords><place><placekey>Twin Cities, Anoka County, Carver County, Dakota County, Hennepin County, Ramsey County, Scott County, Washington County </placekey></place><theme><themekey>transit, buses, bus stops, transportation</themekey></theme></keywords><crossref><citeinfo><title>Transit Routes, transit segments, Transit Shelters, Park and Ride Lots
</title></citeinfo></crossref><accconst>None. This dataset is public domain under the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13). If the dataset is not available from the Online Linkage in Section 6, please contact the Distribution Contact Person.</accconst><useconst>None. This dataset is public domain under the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13).</useconst><ptcontac><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Metropolitan Council</cntorg><cntper>GIS Contact</cntper></cntperp><cntaddr><address>390 Robert Street North</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55101-1805</postal><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype></cntaddr><cntemail>gis-contact@metc.state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></ptcontac></idinfo><dataqual><complete>The stops change log includes all geometry modifications and addition and removal of stop from pattern itinerary starting on a March 25, 2017 effective date forward.</complete><posacc><horizpa><horizpar>Positional accuracy reflects stops and their association with the street centerline network. </horizpar></horizpa></posacc></dataqual><distinfo><distliab>NOTICE:  The Geographic Information System (GIS) Data to which this notice is attached are made available pursuant to the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act (Minnesota Statutes Chapter 13).  THE GIS DATA ARE PROVIDED TO YOU AS IS AND WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY AS TO THEIR PERFORMANCE, MERCHANTABILITY, OR FITNESS FOR ANY PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  The GIS Data were developed by the Metropolitan Council for its own internal business purposes.  The Metropolitan Council does not represent or warrant that the GIS Data or the data documentation are error-free, complete, current, or accurate.  You are responsible for any consequences resulting from your use of the GIS Data or your reliance on the GIS Data.  You should consult the data documentation for this particular GIS Data to determine the limitations of the GIS Data and the precision with which the GIS Data may depict distance, direction, location, or other geographic features.  If you transmit or provide the GIS Data (or any portion of it) to another user, it is recommended that the GIS Data include a copy of this disclaimer and this metadata.</distliab><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Metropolitan Council</cntorg><cntper>GIS Contact</cntper></cntperp><cntaddr><address>390 Robert Street North</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55101-1805</postal><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype></cntaddr><cntemail>gis-contact@metc.state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib></distinfo><metainfo><metd>20230331</metd><metstdn>Minnesota Geographic Metadata Guidelines</metstdn><metstdv>1.2</metstdv><metextns><onlink>http://www.mngeo.state.mn.us/committee/standards/mgmg/metadata.htm</onlink></metextns><metc><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Metropolitan Council</cntorg><cntper>GIS Contact</cntper></cntperp><cntaddr><address>390 Robert Street North</address><city>St. Paul</city><state>MN</state><postal>55101-1805</postal><addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype></cntaddr><cntemail>gis-contact@metc.state.mn.us</cntemail></cntinfo></metc></metainfo><eainfo><overview><eaover>PLEASE NOTE: HASTUS is the schedule-maker software that Metro Transit uses to manage routes and stops.

side_id: The primary key field and unique stop identification number assigned by Metro Transit. 

site_on: The street or address where the stop is found. 

site_at: The cross street or address nearest the stop. 

site_on: The Transit Master system's public name.

corn_desc: The corner location description.

node_id: For those sites that are nodes, this field contains their four letter identification.  Nodes are often timepoints, or places where the bus has to arrive/depart at a certain time.  Note, however, that more than one site can have the same Nodeid because a route will use different sites in different directions. 

city: The city where the stop is found.

effective_date: The date indicating when the modification goes into effect.

r_flag: The remove flag indicates if the stop was removed from pattern itineraries on the effective date.

a_flag: The add flag indicates if the stop was added from pattern itineraries on the effective date.</eaover></overview></eainfo><spref><horizsys><planar><gridsys><gridsysn>Universal Transverse Mercator</gridsysn><utm><utmzone>15</utmzone></utm></gridsys><planci><plandu>meters</plandu></planci></planar><geodetic><horizdn>NAD83</horizdn><ellips>GRS80</ellips></geodetic></horizsys></spref></metadata>